# **CJ WILLIAMS**

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER, FRONT-END DEVELOPER



**Phone** 406.579.1985



Email

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



**Portfolio** 

hirecj.com

# SOCIAL



LinkedIn

/cjwilliamsworks



GitHub

/silencekillsdesign



**Codepen**/silencekillsdesign

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Treehouse Academy**

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com 2013 - 2015

#### **Montana State University**

Graphic Design & Music Technology Bozeman, MT 2003 - 2008

# **SKILLS**

- UX / UI / IA DESIGN
- HTML / CSS / JS / VUE / NUXT
- ADOBE CC & FIGMA
- MANAGEMENT & LEADERSHIP
- SEMRUSH / HUBSPOT
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- E-COMMERCE MANAGEMENT
- PROJECT MANAGEMENT

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- GOOGLE UX DESIGN
- GOOGLE DIGITAL MARKETING
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- CERTIFIED NUXT MASTER
- HUBSPOT INBOUND

# PROFILE

Hi! I'm CJ, a Product Designer, Front-End Web Developer, and E-Commerce Director, with over 11 years of management experience, and over 20 years of creative design experience. I am a strong and compassionate leader with a multi-disciplinary background, able to work and effectively communicate in cross-functional teams fluently. I'm a data-informed and logical decision maker always striving to be better. I'm excited to join a team with shared goals, values, and ethics.

### EXPERIENCE

#### **Greenridge** (Formerly Greenridge Farm)

Director of E-Commerce & Customer Experience / Dec 2022 - Present

- Led product development strategy to increase year-over-year online sales by 400%
- Improved user experience and technical SEO, increasing web traffic over 200%
- Developed design systems, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes in Figma
- Managed web migration, including DNS, CDN, SFTP, SMTP, API integration
- Led creative design on new brand identity, logo, packaging, and digital assets
- Optimized organization-wide operations in product development and design

#### **Hoists.com** (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES)

Director of User Experience and E-Commerce / 2021 - 2023

- Created wireframes, user flows, lo-fi prototypes, and conducted UX research
- Generated \$750k in sales in our first year, amidst major supply chain issues
- Created Information Architecture for over 2500 variable SKU configurations
- Created branding, tagline, and content strategy
- Developed, deployed, and maintained Hoists.com in 6 monthes
- · Managed Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy, budgets, and reporting
- Created infrastructure for Development, Product Design, Sales Support staff
- Managed growth of department, creating 5 new roles within the company

#### SilenceKillsDesign

Agency Owner - Product Design, Front-End Development, Marketing / 2007 - 2020

- UX Research, Prototyping, Architecture, Testing and Design, primarily for B2B
- Designed responsive admin and end-user UX/UI for data validation and address verification SaaS web apps in higher-ed and finance spaces
- Created, managed, and empowered of multiple brands' presence and identity
- Maintained and managed hosting, server setup and cyber security for clients
- Architected, designed, and developed B2B and B2C websites and e-commerce
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting

#### **Xtant Medical** (Formerly Bacterin International)

Manager of UX and Digital Marketing / 2012 - 2016

- Led UX Design, architecture, testing, and development of public-facing site
- Designed and developed investor portals and internal sales portal
- Managed all SEO, SEM, PPC, SMM, Email CAmpaigns, and Ad Purchasing
- · Led Logo & brand design, product design, and growth marketing for rebrand
- Create sales presentations and additional sales support tools for field reps